Derick Fabert

Full Stack Web Developer
Mooresville, IN 46158

(317) 258-0021 glen.fabert@gmail.com github.com/dfabert www.linkedin.com/in/derick-fabert/ dfabert.github.io/DerickFabert

Education

Butler University

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development *December 2020*.

Purdue University

Bachelor of Science, Meteorology August 2007

Synoptic Meteorology and Forecasting track. Took multiple communications classes to improve speaking abilities.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS, Handlebars
- JavaScript, jQuery, ES6+
- GIT, Bootstrap, AJAX, React.js
- Node, Express, MvSql
- Team member development
- Client relations
- Certified Broadcast Meteorologist,
 American Meteorological Society

Recognition

- 2015 Silver Dome Award Best Use of Interactive Media
- 2014 Silver Dome Award
 Best TV

 Weathercaster

Profile

Full stack web developer with experience in management, broadcast meteorology and real estate. Recent graduate of Butler's Web Development Bootcamp and previously received a Bachelor of Science in meteorology from Purdue University. Experience includes leadership roles and development of a weather focused website. Successfully led a weather and news team through several severe weather events, including tornadoes, blizzards, and floods. Passionate about client relations, accuracy and safety. Delighted to be returning to the web development world to solve complex problems using my new and old skills in a fast-paced environment.

Experience

Adams/Fairway/Reagan Outdoor Advertising, Indianapolis
April 2017 – Present, Real Estate Manager/Representative
Effectively oversaw new build projects from start to finish,
searched zoning maps and property for potential areas of
growth, and successfully cultivated and fostered relationships
with lessors. Maintained responsibilities through a corporate
transition in ownership after transferring from a smaller
regional office in Illinois (Adams Outdoor Advertising).

WCIA (CBS), Champaign, IL

April 2010 - April 2017, Chief Meteorologist
Led the weather team and general weather product for news,
managed high-stress situations (including severe weather and
breaking news), and developed and maintained the weather
website. Awarded "most accurate weather team" five straight
years.

University of Illinois, Urbana, IL

April 2011 - April 2017, Adjunct Instructor and Career Advisor Taught a course in broadcast meteorology, advised students on career options, and worked with professors to develop curriculum for aspiring meteorologists. Several students are now working in major markets as broadcast meteorologists.

Web Development Projects

Day Planner | https://dfabert.github.io/DayPlanner/

Deployed Application: https://dfabert.github.io/DayPlanner/

- This Day Planner was a project that will allow the user to plan the day ahead. The text boxes turn different colors if they are the current hour, in the future, or in the past.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.

NBA Dashboard | https://dfabert.github.io/NBADashboard/index.html

Deployed Application: https://dfabert.github.io/NBADashboard/index.html

- When the NBA was in full swing, this application gave updates on the current scores, the standings, and upcoming games. It allows the user to pick a favorite team as well to keep track of.
- Javascript, HTML, APIs, and CSS were all used in this project.

Password Generator | https://dfabert.github.io/PasswordGenerator/PasswordGenerator.html Deployed Application: https://dfabert.github.io/PasswordGenerator/PasswordGenerator.html

- This application uses alerts to create a complicated password for the user.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.

Weather Dashboard | https://dfabert.github.io/WXDashboard/
Deployed Application: https://dfabert.github.io/WXDashboard/

- Weather forecast display that allows the user to view and save different cities for later viewing.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.